

SYLVESTER ARIKHAN

Full-Stack Developer.

A Full-Stack Web Developer with experience in JavaScript MERN stack and building responsive Web and Mobile applications. My background as a Scientist in Chemistry has allowed me to perform quality/assurance, work in a team environment, and put our customers at the forefront of everything. Very interested in learning about Project Management and new technologies. Keeping up team spirit to achieve organizational goals and keep a lasting legacy.

Email: arikhansylvester@gmail.com Address: Koppenstr 18, 10243 Berlin

Phone: 01633731957

Link: https://arikhan.herokuapp.com/

Experience

Sep 2022 - Dec 2022

Frontend Developer (Part Time)

FavFap Germany

• Responsible for developing new user-facing features, determining the structure and design of web pages, building reusable codes, optimizing page loading times, and using JavaScript, Reactjs, and CSS.

Oct 2022 - Nov 2022

Software Developer (Contract)

Consigli AS Oslo/Norway

• Building modern applications using TypeScript, and Reactjs and supporting the company development and testing processes

Feb 2022 - Jul 2022

Software Engineer

Gestalt-Robotics GmbH Berlin/Germany

 Developing, integrating, and testing user interfaces for software in industrial applications.

 $\textbf{Tech stack:} \ \textbf{JavaScript, React.js, SCSS, Storybook, Docker, Websocket, Linux, Git}$

Jun 2020 - Dec 2021

Junior Developer (Intern)

LocaaTech Lagos/Nigeria

- Helped real estate customers buy, rent, or solve daily problems with their property
- Collaborated with senior developers on resolving daily programming task
- Appraised the identified problems on clients' websites and provided solutions using clients' feedback
- Participated and assisted in the testing, maintenance, and upgrade of front and back-end applications

Tech stack: JavaScript, React.js, Angular, SCSS, HTML5, Node.js, MongoDB, postgreSQL, Git

Apr 2021 - Oct 2021

Junior Developer (Bootcamp)

Career Foundry Berlin/Germany

- Completed a 941-hour full-stack development training program under the supervision of industry-leading mentors and tutors
- The project-based program is divided into two parts, Introduction to Front-end development and Full-Stack Immersion
- Studied and trained through a total of 7 achievements from 60 exercises

Projects

- Built the server-side component of a (movies web application). The web application
 provides users information about different movies, directors, and genres. Users
 can sign up, update their personal information, and create a list of their favorite
 movies. http://my-flixdbapp.herokuapp.com/documentation.html
- Using Angular to build the client-side for an application called (myFlix), based on its existing server-side code (REST API and database), with supporting documentation. https://ambabasly.github.io/myFlix-Angular-client/welcome

Dec 2014 - Jul 2017

Assistance Quality Control

AKMA Engineering Nigeria Limited Lagos

- Conducted analysis, synthesized, purified, modified, and characterized chemical and biochemical content before and during production.
- Developed and conducted programs of analysis to ensure quality control of raw materials, chemical intermediates, or final products
- Collected samples and data and analyzed them to identify and quantify environmental toxicants by participating in interdisciplinary research

Education

Feb 2021 - Jan 2023

MBA.-International. Business Management (Part-time)

Ludwigshafen University of Business and Society Ludwigshafen am Rhein, Germany

Thesis title: Influence of agile methodology and organizational culture on service delivery of selected companies in the tech industry.

Sep 2018 - Feb 2021

Master of Sciences in Groundwater Management

Technische Universität Bergakademie Freiberg

Oct 2010 - Oct 2014

Bachelor of Sciences in Chemistry

Ambrose Alli University Ekpoma/Nigeria

Languages

EnglishNative

e

.....

GermanIntermediate

Skills

JavaSrcipt TypeScript
Node.js ReactNative
Docker CSS

React.js MongoDB Test Driven Angular SQL AWS and PWA

Development

Certificates & Courses

- Enterprise Resource Planning (Completed training with university certification)
- Project Management Professional (Completed training with university certification)

Residence permit

• EU Familien angehöriger art 20 rl 2004/38/eg (Gainful Employment Allowed Anywhere Within EU)